Hello, and welcome to Lesson 39
你好 欢迎来到Wolfram U的微积分入门课程第39课
of this introduction to calculus with Wolfram U.
The topic for this lesson is part 1 of a sample calculus exam.
本节课的主题是微积分考试例题的第一部分
Let’s begin with a brief overview of the lesson.
让我们从本课的简单概览开始
In this course, we have gone over lots of topics
在这个课程中 我们已经学过了了很多的主题
in both differential calculus and integral calculus.
在微分微积分和积分微积分中
It’s now time to talk about some exam problems
现在是时候说说考试问题了
to apply what you have learned.
为了应用你所学的知识
The questions I’ll take in this lesson
这节课我要讲的题
are similar to what you might see on the AP Calculus AB exam,
与你在AP微积分AB考试中看到的可能很相似
but equally well, you might see the questions on other exams
同样的 你也会看到其他考试的题目
that you might take anywhere in the world
这样你才能走遍天下无敌手
at an introductory calculus level.
在微积分入门水平上
Let’s begin with the first question,
先说第一个问题
which says find the derivative of this function over here at 2.
它说 找到这个函数的导数在2处
There are two steps over here:
这里有两步
first, find the derivative,
首先 找到导数
and secondly, plug in x = 2.
其次 带入x=2
Now to find the derivative,
首先找导数
what you do is you apply the quotient rule—
你要做的是应用商规则
after all, you have a fraction over there.
毕竟 这么大的一条分数线在那里
The rule says that
该规则规定：
you find the denominator times the derivative of the numerator
找出分母乘分子的导数
minus numerator times derivative of the denominator
分子乘以分母的导数
divided by denominator squared.
除以分母平方
Then of course you plug in the value 2.
当然之后还要带入2
That’s what I’m doing over here.
这就是我这里做的
Then you get back the answer, and you can check the answer with D.
然后得到答案 你可以用D检查答案
You get back just the same result.
得到的是同样的结果
On to question 2, which says calculate the limit
第2题 计算
of this function over here at 5.
这个函数这里 5的极限
Now each term in the function is continuous at 5.
现在函数中的每个项在5处连续
The limit laws say that you can simply plug in the value 5
极限法则说 你可以简单地将数值带入5
and work out the answer, so the answer is just 610 – 6Log[5].
并计算出答案 所以答案只有610-6Log[5]
You can check that with Limit and you get back just the same result.
你可以用Limit检查 得到的结果也是一样的
Here’s a plot which confirms that you actually have
这里画个图 可以证实你其实得到了
the limiting value at that point.
该点的极限值
On to number 3, which says calculate the integral
第3题 是计算
from π to 5 of Cos[x] + 1/x.
Cos[x]+1/x从π到5的积分
Now if you apply the fundamental theorem of calculus,
现在运用微积分的基本定理
then you first find the antiderivative, which is Sin[x] + Log[x].
你首先要找到反导数 也就是Sin[x] + Log[x]
You plug in the upper limit and the lower limit and you subtract,
然后带入上限和下限 然后相减
and you get back the answer.
得到了答案
You can confirm the answer with Integrate,
你可以用Integrate确认答案
which gives you just the same result.
这给你同样的结果
Here is a plot of the region that we just integrated.
这是我们刚才积分的区域图
On to number 4, which says find the value of c
第4题 说的是求c的值
which satisfies the mean value theorem for this function.
其中满足该函数的均值定理
What you need to do is to work out the value of c
您需要做的是计算出c的值
for which you get the mean value for the slope,
你可以得到斜率的平均值
basically, at that point c.
基本上 在这一点c上
First of all, you work out the slope
首先 你要计算出
of the line joining the endpoints.
连接两端点的线的斜率
That’s 13.
是13
Solve the equation—
解方程——
derivative of the function equal to 13 in the given range.
在给定范围内 函数的导数等于13
You get back x as √(7/3).
你得到的x为√（7/3）
Work out the function value.
求出函数值
Basically you have a point
基本上你有一个
at which the mean value theorem is satisfied,
满足均值定理的点
and you can check that with a plot over here.
你可以在这里用Plot函数检查
You see that at that point,
你看 在这一点上
the tangent line has got the same slope
切线和
as the line joining the endpoints.
连接端点的线 斜率是相同的
On to number 5, which says find the general solution
第5题 说的是找到通解
of this differential equation.
来满足这个微分方程
Now that’s a separable differential equation
这是一个可分离的微分方程
because you can separate x and y,
因为你可以把x和y分开
so what you do is think of y' as being dy/dx
所以你要做的是把y'看作是dy/dx
and separate the two sides, and you get back the answer,
并将两边分开 就能得到答案
which you can rewrite as just Exp[Log[–1 + y^2]] = Exp[3x^2 + c].
你可以改写为Exp[Log[-1 + y^2]] = Exp[3x^2 + c]
You have a solution over here, which is y^2 – 1 = c * e^3x^2.
这里有一个解 就是y^2 - 1 = c * e^3x^2
You can plot that solution for different values of c,
你可以绘制不同的c值的解决方案
and here you see that there are all the different solutions.
在这里你可以看到 这里是所有的解决方案
That’s a separable differential equation
那是一个可分离的微分方程
which you can solve by simple integration.
你可以通过简单的积分来解决
Next let’s try and find the limit of this function over here at ∞.
接下来让我们试着在∞这里找到这个函数的极限
Now at ∞, you need to only worry about
现在在∞ 你需要担心的是
the degrees of the numerator and denominator.
分子和分母
Now in this case, they’re the same.
在这种情况下 他们是一样的
They’re both 3, so you simply need to work with those terms.
它们都是3 所以你只需要计算这些项
The answer is going to be 10x^3/3x^3.
答案将是10x^3/3x^3
That gives you just 10/3.
得到10/3
You can check the answer with Limit,
你可以用Limit检查答案
and you do get back just the same result.
得到同样的结果
Here is a plot to visualize what’s happening,
这里有一个图像 可以直观地看到发生了什么
and you do see that the value approaches 10/3, 3.33,
你看 值接近10/3 3.33
as x approaches ∞.
当x接近∞时取得
On to number 7, which says use the trapezoidal rule
第7题 说使用梯形规则
to estimate the integral over here.
来估计这里的积分
Now you are required to use five trapezoids,
要求你使用五个梯形
so what you do is you find the width of each trapezoid
所以你要做的是找到每个梯形的宽度
by doing upper limit minus lower limit over 5,
通过做上限减去下限再除以5
so you get back 8/5 as the width of each trapezoid.
所以你得到8/5 每个梯形的宽度
You then work out the approximate integral
然后计算出近似积分
by adding the areas of these trapezoids.
通过对这些梯形的面积求和得到
Here is the calculation, and I get back the answer 2314.03.
下面是计算结果 我得到的答案是2314.03
Compare that with Integrate.
与Integrate相比
It’s only somewhat close, but not very precise.
有些接近 但不很精确
Here is a plot which shows the actual area
下面是一张图 显示了实际面积
and the trapezoidal approximation.
和梯形近似的面积
Okay. On to question 8, which says find the equation of the line
好 现在进入第8题 找到线段的方程
tangent to the graph of this function at (1, –2).
在(1，-2)处与这个函数的图像相切
Now the first step, of course, is to find the slope at that point.
第一步 当然是要找到该点的斜率
You work out the derivative, which is just e^(x – 1) – 3.
计算导数 是e^(x-1)-3
Plug in x = 1 and you get back the slope as –2.
带入x=1 得到的斜率为-2
You can check that with D.
可以使用D函数检查
Basically you work out the derivative and plug in x = 1,
计算出导数并带入x=1
and you do get back the same answer.
确实得到了同样的答案
By the point-slope formula, the equation on the tangent line
由点斜率公式可知 切线上的方程为
is going to be y minus y1 equal to slope times x minus x1.
是y减去y1等于斜率乘以x减去x1
Here is a plot which shows that you indeed have the correct solution.
这张图可以看出你确实有解对了
On to number 9, which says for what value of a
第9题 说的是求a的值是多少
is this function over here continuous?
这个函数在这边才是连续的？
Now this is a piecewise function.
现在这是一个极端函数
There are two pieces.
有两块
There is the part where x is less than 2 and the remaining part,
有x小于2的部分 其余部分
and the only question is what happens at 2 itself.
而唯一的问题是函数值取2附近时会发生什么
Well, for the function to be continuous, the limit from the left at 2
为了使函数连续 在2的左极限
should be equal to the limit from the right at 2.
应等于在2的右极限
You solve the equation for that,
解这个方程
which is limit as you approach from the left
左极限
equal to limit from the right.
等于右极限
Solve that for a, and you get back a as –1.
对a进行求解 得到a为-1
If a is –1, then you actually have continuity.
如果a是-1 那么你就有连续性
Here’s a plot which shows you that
这里的图 可以告诉你
you indeed have no break in the graph when a is –1.
当a为-1时 你的图形中确实没有断点
You see over here that a is –1.
看这边 a是-1
On to number 10, which says find the approximate value
到了第10题 求近似值
of this square root to four decimal places.
这个平方根 精确到小数点后四位
Well, keep in mind that the number given to you is very close to √144,
请记住 给你的这个数字是非常接近√144的
so that’s 12, so you need to work with the function √x
因此 这是12 所以你需要用函数√x工作
as the underlying function at the point (144, 12).
作为该点的基本函数（144 12）
You first work out the slope at that point.
先计算出那个点的斜率
Write the equation of the tangent line,
写出切线的方程
and then use that to write the approximation,
然后用它来计算近似值
which is going to be 12 plus the difference over here over 24.
这将是12加上一个东西 是这个数字除以24
Let’s check how it compares with the actual value.
让我们来看看它与实际值的比较
You see over here that you actually have
你看这里 你实际上的
an error which is in the tenth millions.
误差只有千万分之一
Okay. Let’s go on to number 11,
好的 我们继续看第11
which says find the volume of the solid,
找到固体的体积
which you can obtain by rotating this function around the y axis.
这个体积可以通过围绕y轴旋转这个函数来获得
Then you bound it by the y axis itself
然后计算在y轴本身
and the line x = 2 and the x axis.
和线段x=2和x轴之间的区域
Here’s a plot of the region.
这是一个区域的图像
Now in this case because you’re revolving around the y,
现在在这种情况下 因为你是围绕着y旋转的
you use the cylindrical shell method.
应该使用柱面坐标系
Basically you have cylinders of radii x and height –x^3 + 5x,
你有半径x和高度-x^3+5x的圆柱体
so that’s the integral to be computed over here.
所以这边要计算的是积分
There’s 2πr * hdx.
2πr*hdx
Work it out with Integrate, and you get back the volume required.
用Integrate解决 你就能得到所需的体积
On to number 12, which says find the extrema of this function
第12题 要找出这个函数的极值
on the interval [2, 6] using the closed interval method.
在[2，6]的闭区间上
Now because you have a polynomial, it’s in fact differentiable,
这是一个多项式 所以它是可以微分的
so the first step is to find the critical numbers,
所以第一步就是要找到临界点
and those are the numbers with slope 0.
也就是是斜率为0的地方
What you do is you find a derivative, set it equal to 0
你要做的是求导 让它等于0
and solve in the given interval for the values of x.
并在给定区间内求解x的值
We just find one value, x is 3, so you must check at 2, at 3 and at 6.
我们只找到了一个值 x是3 所以在2处、3处和6处进行检查
Here’s the function.
这个函数
Work out the value at those three points, and you see now that
我们计算出这三点的值 你看到的是
you have a maximum over here and a minimum over there,
这里是最大值 这里是最小值
so you have a maximum at (3, –9) and a minimum at (6, –108).
所以你的最大值在（3，-9） 最小值在（6，-108）
You can check that with a plot.
你可以用Plot函数来检查
You can see you have a maximum at 3 and a minimum at 6.
你可以看到最高点是3 最低点是6
On to number 13, which says find the derivative
第13题 它说要找到这里这个函数的导数
of this function over here.
Now the function has two terms, so for the first term,
现在函数有两项 所以对于第一项
you use the product rule, and you get back the first term
你使用乘法规则 你得到 第一个项
times derivative of second term
乘以第二项的导数
plus second term times derivative of first.
加上第二项乘以第一项的导数
Then you work out the second-term derivative in the same way.
用同样的方法计算出第二项的导数
Get the answer, and then by the difference rule for derivatives,
得到答案 再由差法则求导数
you simply subtract them like over here to get back the final result.
只需像这里一样减去它们 就能得到最终结果
You can check that with D,
你可以用D函数检查
and you see that it does just the same thing.
你看 答案确实如此
That brings me to the end of the first part
第一部分的微积分考试样本就到此结束了
of the sample calculus exam.
Do review it.
记得复习
These are not very difficult questions.
这些都不是很困难的问题
The next part will have some more challenging questions,
下一部分会有一些更具挑战性的问题
but by then,
到那时
I hope you’ll be ready to take up those more difficult questions.
我希望你能准备好接受那些更难的问题
Thank you very much. I’ll stop over here.
这节课到这就结束了 谢谢观看
校译 氘化氢